There comes a time to cut loose
Footloose is a drama, music, romance film directed by Craig Brewer.
Ren MacCormack is transplanted from Boston to the small southern town
of Bomont where loud music and dancing are prohibited.
Not one to bow to the status quo, Ren challenges the ban, revitalizing the town and
falling in love with the minister’s troubled daughter Ariel in the process.
Rev. Shaw Moore, played by Dennis Quaid.
Ren MacCormack, played by Kenny Wormald.
Ariel Moore, played by Julianne Hough.
Vi Moore, played by Andie MacDowell.
Willard Hewitt, played by Miles Teller.
Wes Warnicker, played by Ray McKinnon.
Footloose is a 2011 American musical drama film directed by Craig
Brewer, who co-wrote the screenplay with Dean Pitchford.
A remake of the 1984 film, the film stars Kenny Wormald,
Julianne Hough, Andie MacDowell, and Dennis Quaid.
The film follows a young man who moves from Boston to a small
Southern town and protests the town's ban against dancing.
Filming took place from September to November 2010 in Georgia.
The film was released in Australia and New Zealand on October 6, 2011, and
in North America on October 14, 2011 by Paramount Pictures.
The film received mixed reviews and grossed $15.5 million in
its opening weekend and $63 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of dancing, dance, dancer, remake, prom.
The tone is emotional.